okay so in this video I want to go
through a recent talk that I gave at
Google for machine learning Singapore
and the whole idea is around in context
learning new llms and summarization and
showing you some behind the scenes of a
little app that I built to test some of
these things out so kicking off things I
would say what I'm talking about and
what we're sort of interested in at the
moment is llm apps and I don't know what
version of kind of the llm stack and LM
apps that we're working on but it
certainly feels like it's probably
version seven now going back to the
original LMS that we were using in 2018
gpt2 apps and llms in 2019 and then
progressing right up to nowadays with
the latest open a gp4 Gemini and
fantastic open source models like llama
3 Etc as we're going through this I
think there are some key themes though
that we can take away for developing
these apps and for me personally the two
big interests that I've got here around
llm apps are around personalization and
curation so I see these as being two of
a number of things that are really
changing to allow people to take use of
this kind of Technology more and more so
when I'm talking about
personalization again here I'm talking
about like the idea of how to make
things the way you like them and LS open
up a whole world for this we've got the
ability ility to do personalized
interactions we can do personalized
results so that every user gets a
different set of results and stuff like
that an example of the personalized sort
of interactions can be things like
personalized levels so when someone's
learning something rather than just have
level one level two level three you can
actually make it so it can work out
where the person's at and teach to that
and support them at the level that
they're at and grow their skills with
this kind of thing so this idea of
personalization I see as being a huge
factor in building llm apps nowadays the
second area that I think is really
interesting is the whole idea of
curation I think it's pretty obvious to
most people that we're all well beyond
data overload nowadays there's just so
much data out there that there's no way
we can keep up with watching you know
all the the YouTube videos with reading
blog articles with all this kind of
thing so really this is where agents and
llm apps can be like a filter on the
world for us that they can go out look
at source material bring stuff back use
that the whole idea here is that we
really want to get what we need when we
need it and try to filter out a lot of
the other stuff that's going on here and
this brings me to a recent app that I
built that I really wanted something
that did really good high quality notes
of YouTube videos and other content and
I started out with YouTube videos but
I've added into this over time as you go
through now one of the challenges for
most sort of summarization and stuff
like that is you end up with very short
summaries of videos and actually what
I'm more interested than just a summary
I'm actually interested in a set of
notes so this is an example of one of
the Stanford overview on Transformers
video you can see here that I've
basically got a system where I'm
building like a whole bunch of different
notes around different sections of the
video going through and putting this
together something that I've been
looking at and working on for quite a
while with different levels of success
in here the whole idea for doing
something like this is that we can
basically give it you know a transcript
with timestamps and then it can turn
that into a full set of notes that we
can use for a variety of different
things and so that this sort of brings
us the whole sort of curation aspect
that I'm interested in but then the
other thing that I'm interested in as
well is that often you want notes that
are different sometimes you want a full
set of notes sometimes you just want a
very short summary sometimes you want
action items for going through this and
then on top of that you often want to
basically pick a sort of context that
you want the notes in so if I want a set
of notes as an AI researcher that's
quite different than the set of notes
that maybe if I'm trying to skim to
learn a new topic or a new subject I
want a set of notes that sort of
highlight the statistics mentioned in
there as opposed to just general notes
this is the sort of personalization
aspect coming into play here so in the
app here you can basically come in to
your account and you can set up
different kinds of profiles so the idea
here is that you can set up a profile
that sets up key sorts of things that
are interesting to you to get the
information out for a summary and you
can combine that with a summary type to
get a better level of summarization
and a better level of personalized
curation that's what I'm going for here
now the the key thing is what I want to
talk about more is like some of the key
things around what it took to build
something like this and also
fundamentally the sort of new way of
thinking about building some of these
apps and certainly how I've changed over
the last few months now to get into that
we need to talk about like the state of
llms so if we go back in history a bit
the idea was that we had a bunch of sort
of Foundation models if we go back a
year or two you had some Foundation
models from Google you had some
Foundation models from open AI maybe one
or two other companies there the key
thing though was that in these
Foundation models that everyone was
focused on the best quality model now
even though the organizations may have
had different versions of the model at
different tiers and stuff like that
often they didn't make those public if
we jump forward to now we see that okay
there's still the big players are still
the same but we've now got the addition
of a lot of other models coming into the
scene here and these models have caused
everyone to re-evaluate how you're
actually picking a model how you're
doing things like this so I'd say that
now we're starting to fall into these
categories of best model best quality
model which is what most people still
judge things about meaning usually the
biggest model with the best scores on ML
Lu with the best scores on gsm 8K that
kind of thing and then at the other end
of the the Spectrum which I'm going to
talk about in a sec is this whole idea
of smaller proprietary models that are
still way bigger than most of the
open-source models but they're much
faster they can still be used for lots
of different tasks and they end up being
much cheaper unfortunately there's some
models that end up being in the middle
here so you end up with a bunch of these
models that are in the middle here and
they suffer from being too big to
perhaps run easily quickly cheaply fast
or they're just not good quality models
and meaning that they're too big that if
you look at models on par with them
they're just so much better that it's
very hard to justify running a lot of
these models for this so I think with
llama 3 coming out recently we've seen a
lot of the sort of model developers just
really become a lot less relevant here
in in this sort of situation because
people can use llama 3 they can use
other models if they want to run
something small and local or they can go
for the really big ones if they want the
most intelligent model there but being a
big model that's not in the top tier of
intelligence out there really means that
for a lot of people it's not going to be
a really relevant kind of thing so we've
also seen this move to
having families of models so Google
wasn't the first one to do this but when
Gemini announced they basically had a
whole sort of Suite of models in here
and so they've you know got Gemini Ultra
1.0 Gemini Pro 1.0 the Gemini Nano
models which are really more for mobile
so I'm not going to count them too much
in this and then you've got things like
Pro 1.5 where they blew out the context
window for the first time to have sort
of a million token context window which
is totally awesome it allows for you to
do a lot of different multimodal things
of video of audio does it kill rag no
not at all this is I think becoming more
and more clear to people that rag is
still going to be around for a long time
the challenge with models like Gemini
Pro
1.5 is that firstly just the speed is
that it's pretty slow if you put a
million tokens in there it's going to
take a few minutes to give you an answer
for that and the second biggest sort of
issue with this is that when you're
doing something out you're only getting
8,000 tokens you're not getting like a
full million tokens in million tokens
possibly or even a million tokens in
100,000 you're getting 8K out that means
that currently in the state that they're
in now these models and it's not just
the Gemini ones it's from other
providers as well are not something that
you can basically use for a long output
so if you think about it there are lots
of use cas for long outputs out there if
you want to write a book or more
importantly if you want to edit a book
where you basically give it a whole book
to and have it go through and change all
the time it sees a name or something
like that or do certain kinds of things
in there that perhaps a little bit more
complicated than just find and replace
it would be great if we could go 100,000
tokens in 100,000 tokens out at a time
but unfortunately that's not the case
another use case of this would be
transcribing long audio so why while
Gemini 1.5 Pro can take in 10 hours of
audio it's not like you can get a
transcript of that out because that's
going to be greater than the 8,000
tokens in here and one of the biggest
use cases that I've personally been
looking for is a way of how can we get
long summaries and long forms of note
taking and this is what this is all
about in here so recently samman said
something like this I'm paraphrasing it
a little bit that he said that there are
two main strategies for building on AI
right assume the models will not improve
much and build things on top of current
capabilities which I think he said that
if you do that open AI will steamroll
you for doing that or B build assuming
open AI will keep improving the models
that at a rapid Pace I think there's
like a middle ground here there's
actually a third option that yes the
models are definitely going to get
better this year we're going to see
better models out with perhaps new GPT
models new Gemini models new Claude
models later in the year that kind of
thing but even with those models getting
better we have to ship products with
what we've got now and we have to find
new ways to be able to do things with
what we've got now and this brings me to
the idea of making use of this new class
of model that's coming out so the one
that I'm going to focus on is Hau in
here but there are others coming from
other players as well this is I think
Haiku was probably
one of the first ones out like this so
the thing that I would say about this
new sort of tier of models is that these
models are getting very strong
benchmarks they're not the best so for
example in the Claude 3 obviously the
Opus model is the big model with Sonet
being the middle one Hau being lower one
these new models are not the best models
out there but they have very strong
benchmarks and on top of those
benchmarks they're super performant
meaning that their speed is really good
they have still have very big context
windows for putting things in and
generally the tokens are going to be
quite cheap in this so if we look at why
kou that I'm focusing on here is that
we've got something that one is
multimodal that two we've got a really
long context window if we want to go out
to that context window we've got
something that is super cheap in here if
we look at the the pricing in here we
can see that Hau is only 25 cents per
million tokens input and 125 per million
tokens output comparing that to the top
of the line where it's
$15 for the input tokens and $75 out for
the output tokens so this cheapness
allows us to do a lot of different
things and then the speed comes in
totally you know for this the whole idea
of having a very fast model really
changes the game in what you can do with
these kind of things now the other sort
of example of this that I would say that
we're seeing at the moment which is
pretty good is meta's Lama 3 Model on
Gro or powered by grock as they like to
say so that basically allows you to get
very fast tokens out it's very
performant in these kind of ways and we
know that the Llama 3 model 70 billion
model is actually a very good model for
long stuff the only issue with this one
currently is the lack of multimodality
if you wanted to to do something with
images in so there are some challenges
that come with using Hau for start
you're often going to need to tune your
prompts a bit more you're going to need
different prompts than the open AI
models one of the biggest challenges
though is actually getting quter at the
moment from providers to do lots of
calls so if you're going to put
something into production getting quoter
on gcp whether it's a version of haiku
on Bedrock on AWS get a there and even
from anthropic themselves you're
generally going to be pretty limited
about the number of queries per minute
that you can actually do for this and as
I'm going to show you with this
summarization app that becomes actually
quite important that yes each call to
the LM is going to be you know
incredibly cheaper than it was before
but we're going to make a lot more calls
to the llm as we go through this and do
this so if you want to tune prompts for
this go and have a look at the meta
prompt I a whole the metap promp for for
Claude 3 I did a whole video about this
this is where it basically writes The
Prompt for you it goes through and does
a number of different things if you're
interested in that check out the video
for for that hi's got some other
interesting things in that you should be
using XML tags with it it tends seems to
respond a lot better to XML tags than to
Jason for putting things in and out on
the whole though that's not something
that's really key and then the the sort
of last thing I would say is so when
we're talking about this new area of
smaller proprietary models that's out
there one of the biggest advantages here
is that you can basically add more in
context learning right so you can add
more few shot examples and where in the
past people would go for sort of three
shot or five shot maybe eight shot for
the few shot
examples now it's not a big deal to go
for 20 30 50 different examples in here
and recently there was a really
interesting paper that came out that
came out from Google deep mine called
many shot in context learning and the
idea here in the paper is that they
rather than where conventionally people
are using three to eight sort of
examples they started what would happen
if you went to 50 examples if you went
to 500 if you went to 2,000 examples
here and you can see that for a variety
of different benchmarks that they looked
at just massively increasing the number
of exemplars or examples that they're
passing in allowed the models to do a
lot better so you can see a bump for the
many shot Ico versions now you can see
that some of these are going like 512
examples 128 50 248 Etc and the thing is
there's also been some papers that are
showing some really interesting things
that the more few shot examples you're
using you're actually then starting to
make it more like you're fine-tuning the
model in the way that you want it to go
as well that seems to be the case
especially with these proprietary models
often perhaps even more so than the
open-source models that are out there so
using exemplars and examples in Hau is a
really good thing that you can do to
basically guide the model and you tend
to wrap them in XML tags here so you can
see I've got an example here are eight
examples of great math with step by step
then we just wrap them and stuff like
that the model then is able to work this
out and it's going to then be much more
primed to give a better response on
these kind of things now this not only
works for things like this it also works
for things like any sort of function
calling any sort of react prompting
anything where you're trying to get it
to make decisions and stuff the more
examples that you can stuff in there the
better the quality that you get coming
out of there all right and this brings
us to summarization so I showed you the
app a little bit before here
summarization has been a challenge for
natural language understanding and
natural language processing people for
quite a long time now in the past
everything was extractive versus
abstractive you know with extractive
being where you're basically just
pulling out sentences from the original
document or from what someone said on a
video that kind of thing and abstractive
has been where we're doing like
rewriting for this kind of thing but I'm
going to say that nowadays you actually
want to think about summarization in
some different ways most summarization
now is going to be abstractive
summarization but you really want to
think about summarization as
personalized summarization so this is
tailoring the summaries to user
preferences or user interests
aspect-based
summarization where you're getting the
summary to include very specific things
like facts and figures statistics that
kind of thing so that it doesn't try and
summarize those Concepts it puts those
in as it's sort of getting them and then
there's a whole sort of field of
dialogue summarization that when you're
actually building something to summarize
interviews and conversations is actually
quite different than when you're trying
to just summarize General presentations
or teaching videos that kind of thing so
let's look at some of the ways that
people do summarization with M so the
best way if you can do it is basically
just to have your input documents a
prompt going into the llm and then
coming out with the summary in one shot
this is what we would call Simple
stuffing for this and while this can get
really good results the challenge here
is that you can't do it for really big
documents and certainly in the past
people couldn't do this so in the past
one of the big things people did was map
produce so where You' basically take
your document you break it up into to
chunks you then pass the chunks through
one at a time to the llm with a prompt
and you get multiple summaries out which
you then combine in some way shape or
form this has been very you know popular
with Lang chain from the start people
used this kind of thing the biggest
challenge that you have here is that if
you have something in chunk number two
that refers to Something in chunk number
seven those are not in context at the
same time so it's much harder for it to
be able to pick up that you should be
taking this and you should be taking
something else in in there a sort of
variation on this that people used a lot
to was refining over calls so each time
we're passing in our summary and adding
to it and keeping what we had from
before deciding what is more important
that kind of for going through this
there are also techniques where people
do reranking of of the chunks to work
out which chunks are the ones with the
most
with the best information in there so
what I want to show you is a new way
that I've been doing summarization for
this app and how it works going through
this so because you're using something
like Hau where it's quite cheap Etc
you're going to do multiple calls to the
llm but the calls are going to be
slightly different than just something
like map produce or something so the
first call is going to basically get
sort of sectioning information from this
now if I go back to the example that we
had here you can see that we've got
sections being extracted out those are
not fixed sections the model is deciding
when the topic changes from one thing to
another so this whole idea is what I
would call sectioning so our first call
would be like a sectioning call then
what we do is we basically pass in the
full document for each time but tell it
just to summarize that particular
section so we give it the time stamps
and stuff like that and so the summary
that it's put out here is just for this
section even though I'm giving it the
full document the advantage of this is
that if something in that part of the
document refers to another section it's
got that in its context learning that it
can actually use that to still summarize
this section in here so you've got the
advantage because we've got these long
context Windows of being able to put in
full 30,000 tokens or something for a
YouTube video but then we've got the
benefit of basically getting out
individual summaries which when combined
can be far longer than the 8,000 token
window that we get out for something
like this so using Haiku here allows us
to get a very large amount of input
tokens very cheap Hau itself is good
enough generally to discover the
sections if you wanted a better way of
getting the sections you can actually go
for a bigger model for that first call
to get your sections and then just pass
it into the Hau for the rest again here
because you're using a model which is
extremely cheap and still very fast you
shouldn't be afraid of having long
prompts or long contacts in there not
only can you put the full context of the
the video in there you can also put a
bunch of different fuse shot examples in
there of how you want certain things to
be pulled out for it for that kind of
thing and this stage like 40,000 tokens
is only going to be one cent for this so
this is something that you should think
about as well and then finally one of
the things that you can do with some of
the models is that you can do a lot of
these calls in parallel so once we've
got this call done none of these calls
are actually reliant on each other they
basically just rely on that first call
that we've got there so that allows you
to do a lot of things in parallel as you
go through this so you can see here's an
example of some of the sectioning that
comes out where I'm getting it returning
each section in an XML tag it's got the
timestamp in there it's got a whole
bunch of things in there as we go
through this and if you get your prompt
you should get the sections for the
entire thing as we go through in here
all right so the advantages of doing
this is that you can get an llm to focus
just on just a section but in the
context of the full document that you've
got going here this is a big Advantage
for getting better quality summaries you
can pass the entire transcript document
article something in you can get longer
summaries at end that go Way Beyond
8,000 tokens or rather longer sets of
notes at the end that go Way Beyond the
8,000 tokens what are the disadvantages
of this definitely it's using a lot more
tokens that's not such a big issue
though when you've got something like
Hau where the tokens are just so cheap
probably the biggest disadvantage is
that the more calls that you need are
not going to be that the price is not
going to be the big thing there but just
making sure that you've got quota to do
calls so when I opened up the summary
app for some test users one of the
things was it started crashing because
it was going beyond the 60 queries per
minute that it was allowed to do on that
platform and something like that so you
will need to basically if you're going
to put something into production you'll
need to make sure that you can get
access to more quota for this kind of
thing in conclusion just to finish up I
would say that you really should be
evaluating your llms the choice of llm
that you're picking not just on academic
benchmarks or something like that and
not just even on picking the best model
all the time you really want to pick the
model that is right for the level of use
that you're going to use and often
that's going to mean that you're going
to pick a smaller variant of a
proprietary model that is going to be
very fast and very cheap for this now
yes you can run open source models and
stuff like that for most people while
there's certainly other cases for that I
would say for most people you're
actually going to be much better off
just going with a service provider that
gives you a sort of fixed price per
token for doing this rather than having
to pay for GPU time that often perhaps
you don't need or you only need parts it
that kind of another conclusion I would
say is don't be afraid to use lots of
tokens for inputs I see this time and
time again that people are constantly
trying to prune their prompts to try and
save money and stuff like that usually
more often than not that actually just
means you end up getting worse results
so you're better to go for the cheaper
model and actually use more tokens than
just trying to basically budget your
tokens on a really big model use the big
models when the cheap models fail so for
certain things you will need a big model
but the cheaper models things like High
and and there are others coming from the
big providers and stuff like that these
models are getting smarter and smarter
with each iterations so that these sort
of second or third tier but really fast
models are now you know well beyond
models that we were using a year ago for
doing this kind of thing adding to this
I would say that context is often far
more important than choosing the best
llm think about that when you're
building your app and and doing those
various things in and finally then just
think about how you're calling the model
rather than just one call to do one
thing with the introduction of these
sort of smaller models and with the
introduction of things like llama 3 70
billion on grop suddenly now we really
want to be thinking about multiple calls
often to do one thing and that can be
things like where you're including
checking the output self-reflection
reflexion that kind of thing that can be
tool use checking tools checking
function calls that kind of thing but
you can have multiple calls that are
very quick on these platforms like grock
and still using a really good solid
model like llama 370 billion in there so
anyway hopefully this was useful in
getting you to understand some of the
changes that we're seeing in the llm
space at the moment and I'm pretty sure
you're going to see these choices roll
out even more over the next few months
Etc
for this all right as always if you've
got any comments please put them in the
comments below any questions put them
there as well if you found the video
useful please click like And subscribe
and I will talk to you in the next video
bye for now